{
    "id": "e4c2d60aa74e4f2d94affd7cfcb921e0",
    "title": "Prepositions Exercise",
    "questions": [
        {
            "question": "She went to school ……………….. Frankfurt.",
            "description": "After expressions like go to school, we use in. Sometimes at is also possible.",
            "answers": [
                "in",
                "to",
                "into"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "c5f3054538e14fd499e3427746403e62"
        },
        {
            "question": "We arrived ………………………… Shanghai on Monday morning.",
            "description": "After arrive we use in or at.",
            "answers": [
                "at",
                "in",
                "to"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "edb6c79acbda4d8eba8fb584404243d7"
        },
        {
            "question": "Due to his extravagant lifestyle, he landed himself ………………………….. deep trouble.",
            "description": "We use in / at after land.",
            "answers": [
                "to",
                "on",
                "in"
            ],
            "correct": 2,
            "id": "f6195942e3c64446b8d90cb1192a7203"
        },
        {
            "question": "I broke the stick ………………………..",
            "description": "In half is the correct expression here.",
            "answers": [
                "by half",
                "in half",
                "into half"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "15ad7e814aa945d081e6cdebbf1e6f81"
        },
        {
            "question": "She cut the vegetables ………………………… small pieces.",
            "description": "Cut can be followed by in or into.",
            "answers": [
                "in",
                "to",
                "into"
            ],
            "correct": 2,
            "id": "51f84a7f6e96440f8fee542999977b66"
        },
        {
            "question": "She threw another log …………………… the fire.",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "in",
                "at",
                "on"
            ],
            "correct": 2,
            "id": "5076656ca9de4f0791cbf2db3bd546e1"
        },
        {
            "question": "She performed well …………………………. having a headache.",
            "description": "In spite of is a preposition. We need a preposition before a noun or ing form.",
            "answers": [
                "in spite",
                "despite of",
                "in spite of"
            ],
            "correct": 2,
            "id": "70cb5a50e8ea4deab0698eb440191a33"
        },
        {
            "question": "He threw the ball ………………………. the window.",
            "description": "Out of is the opposite of into. Out without of is possible in an informal style.\r\n",
            "answers": [
                "out",
                "out of",
                "off"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "c3e5212dfe32496184338a9373128bb3"
        },
        {
            "question": "Don’t marry him. Marry me ………………………..",
            "description": "Instead without of is an adverb. It usually goes at the beginning or at the end of a clause.",
            "answers": [
                "instead",
                "instead of",
                "Either could be used here"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "c233bb9cc0164aa8bf3c6fbd9efc942c"
        },
        {
            "question": "He watched TV all day …………………….. going to work.",
            "description": "Instead of is a preposition. It can be followed by a noun or an ing form. Without is not used with this meaning. ",
            "answers": [
                "Instead",
                "Instead of",
                "without"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "22a6fbd0a10947b1802b3ea735d71349"
        },
        {
            "question": "He tripped ……………………….. the cat and fell downstairs.",
            "description": "The verb tripped is followed by the preposition over. ",
            "answers": [
                "on",
                "over",
                "off"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "c2cdb528e17d4f279cec5af56475d1d9"
        },
        {
            "question": "I am sorry ………………………… breaking your window.",
            "description": "Sorry can be followed by for or about. ",
            "answers": [
                "for",
                "about",
                "Either could be used here"
            ],
            "correct": 2,
            "id": "b0e7252a161d4fde8b412986c950437f"
        }
    ]
}